Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Dance Records, 1962-2011
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Dance Records, 1962-2011
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. Dept. of Dance. Office of the Chairperson
UWM Archival Collection 30
2.6 cubic ft. (4 boxes)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Records consist of correspondence, faculty meeting minutes, curriculum guidelines, and programs from various dance performances. The chair's correspondence is primarily to the dean of the School of Fine Arts relating to curriculum changes, personnel requests, and other department activities. The faculty meeting minutes document course requirements, budget cuts, faculty appointments, unrestricted student evaluations of faculty, and upcoming student and faculty dance performances. The files also contain information on guest artists who performed with the Dance Department along with appearances by several nationally renowned dance companies. Other records in the collection include information on the development of the Milwaukee Ballet Company and its association with the School of Fine Arts.
The Department of Dance was created in the fall of 1965, three years after the creation of the School of Fine Arts. In 1982, the department merged with the Department of Theatre Arts to form the Department of Theatre and Dance.
Department Chairs
1965-1969 Myron Nadel
1969-1974 Susan Spalding
1974-1975 Carla Graham-White
1975-1977 Gloria Gustafson
1977-1979 Martha Myers
1979-1982 Marcia Schramm Purdy
1982-1988 Sanford Robbins
1988-1989 LeRoy Stoner
1989-1997 Malcolm Morrison
1997-2003 LeRoy Stoner
2003-2004 Edward Burgess
2004-2005 Leslie Vansen
2005-2007 Pamela Rehberg
2007-2010 Janet Lilly
2010-2012 Ed Burgess
2012- Simone Ferro
The files are organized alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
Related Material in the UWM Libraries
UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Theatre and Dance Records UWM Archival Collection 85
UW-Milwaukee Peck School of the Arts Records UWM Archival Collection 81
Administrative/Restriction Information
There are no access restrictions on the materials, and the collection is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
The collection originally consisted of five series of faculty minutes, correspondence, and subject files acquired before 1989. The department transferred additional materials to the Archives in October 2012 (accession 2012-026).
Contents List
- Advising, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Artists in Residence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ballet Repertory Company, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bar Harbor Festival Ballet, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bauer Dance Ensemble, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bennington Dance Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Budget Advisory Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Center for 20th Century Studies, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Chairpersons Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Chicago Contemporary Dance Theatre, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Community Outreach and Recruitment Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1965-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Course and Curriculum Committee, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Curriculum, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
- Dance Notation Bureau, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Dance Performances, Planning and Preparation, 1965-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
- Dance Therapy Seminar Questionnaire Answers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Eleo Pomare Dance Company, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Erick Hawkins Dance Company, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Executive Committee
  - 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - 2003-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Faculty Meeting Minutes
  - 1966-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26-29)
  - 2002-2009 (Box 3, Folder 4-26)
  - 2009-2011 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Fine Arts Course and Curriculum Committee, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- First Chamber Dance Company, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Grant Requests, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Guest Artists
  - 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Inter-Arts Committee, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Jose Limon Dance Company, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Lecture Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Milwaukee Ballet Company, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Milwaukee Modern Dance Council, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Program Committee, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Programs, 1962-1975 (Box 1, Folder 41-45)
- Sanasardo Dance Company, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scholarships, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Student Dance Ensemble, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Studios, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Teacher Certification Program, 1966-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Theory and Criticism, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)